Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Collections of Artwork & Associated Material, 1850-1962; Series III; 22.74; (21 boxes)
  - MCILWRAITH, WILLIAM FORSYTH
    - Etching Plates
      - "Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo." [Detail]. Zinc, 29.1 x 21 cm. (Box 23, Folder 475)
      - "Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo." Copper, 23.2 x 23 cm. (Box 23, Folder 476)
      - "Loading Logs." Zinc, 26.6 x 17.4 cm., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 477)
      - "Mt. Hood aquatint?" Zinc, 28.7 x 21.5 cm. (Box 23, Folder 478)
      - "Mt. Hood in August." Zinc, 27.9 x 19.1 cm. (Box 23, Folder 479)
      - "Portland Water Front." Zinc, 19 x 24 cm. (Box 24, Folder 480)
        Same image as "Boats tied up at Pier. Seattle & Portland Boats named" in box 20, folder 440
      - "Portland Water Front" [different view]. Zinc, 25.5 x 19 cm. (Box 24, Folder 481)
      - "Portland Water Front" [another different view]. Zinc, 20.8 x 15.8 cm. (Box 24, Folder 481a)
      - "River front scene." Zinc, 16.1 x 10.8 cm. (Box 24, Folder 482)
      - "St. Johns Bridge." Zinc, 30.2 x 20.3 cm. (Box 24, Folder 483)
      - "Scissors Grinder." Zinc, 29.1 x 18.8 cm. (Box 24, Folder 484)
      - "Temple Beth Israel." Copper, 26.5 x 20.1 cm., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 485)
      - "Temple Beth Israel, Portland, Ore." Copper, 15.5 x 11.4 cm. (Box 25, Folder 486)
        Title from plate
      - "Timberline Lodge." Zinc, 23.8 x 36.7 cm. (Box 25, Folder 487)
      - "The Trouble Shooter." Copper, 23.1 x 15.1 cm., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 488)
      - [Under the Bridge.] Zinc, 19 x 12.9 cm. (Box 25, Folder 489)
  - PAXSON, E. S. (Edgar Samuel)
    - Artwork
      - Original Artwork
        - [After the Fight.] Oil painting, 34.5 x 50.3 cm. in frame 50.7 x 66.5 cm., 1911
          Signed. Title from Sotheby's auction catalog dated June 24, 1980: Fine American Western Paintings: The Collection of Dr. and Mrs. Franz Stenzel
        - "Burial on the Plains, 1852." Oil painting (grisaille), 45.5 x 61.5 cm. in frame 65 x 79.5 cm., 1902
        - "Crow Indian Camp." Oil painting (grisaille), 38 x 29.6 cm. in frame 56.5 x 45 cm. (irreg.)
        - "Injens by Paxson." Empty portfolio with pen-and-ink drawing of a Native American chief on front cover, 36.7 x 29.5 cm. (Box 26, Folder 490)
        - "Pap-oose." Pen-and-ink drawing in a small booklet with "Miss Dolly. A Merry Xmas -1903-" written on front, 12 x 6.2 cm.
          Signed. With tied leather loop at top
        - "Phillippines 1908-9." Sketchbook containing eleven sketches in pencil, 14 x 22 cm., [1898-1909]
        - [A shot from the cabin.] Oil painting (grisaille), 55 x 39 cm. in frame 74 x 59 cm., 1901
          Signed. Title from Stenzel's notes
      - Prints
        - [Cree Indian.] Color print, 23 x 16.5 cm. (Box 26, Folder 491)
        - "Curley." Color print, 29.2 x 36.2 cm. and smaller (Box 26, Folder 492)
          Two images, one with four inset prints at corners of "Cree," "Apache," "Sioux," and "Crow"
        - "A Hunt in 'Ye Olden Time.'" Color print, 24 x 30.4 cm. on sheet 28.2 x 36 cm., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 493)
        - "Paxson Indian Head." Color print, 27.9 x 28.8 cm. (Box 26, Folder 494)
        - "A Sioux." Color print, 15 x 10 cm., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 495)
        - Three color prints mounted together: "Apache," "Crow," and "A Nez Perce," 13.3 x 8.9 cm. each on sheet 20.7 x 34.2 cm. (Box 26, Folder 496)
        - Three color prints mounted together: "Curley, Custer's Scout," "Flathead," and "Mis-sou-la," visible oval image 13 x 8.5 cm. each on sheet 18 x 34.4 cm. (Box 26, Folder 497)
    - Printed Material
      - E. S. Paxson business cards and studio stationery (Box 27, Folder 498)
      - Annie Oakley's Christmas card, 1891 (Box 27, Folder 499)
      - Postcards (19) depicting nine different Paxson paintings. Color prints, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 500)
    - Photographs and Portraits
      - Tintype of Paxson with Mexican Americans, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 501)
      - Photograph of Jack Crawford, inscribed to E. S. Paxson, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 502)
      - Woodcut (proof) of Paxson by Merle Davis, 27.6 x 21.7 cm., 1917 (Box 27, Folder 503)
    - Other Papers
      - "Custer Battle Notes by E. S. Paxson, Butte, Mont." Notebook, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 504)
      - Lease of Paxson's painting "Custer's Last Battle" to William S. Brackett, 1899 Dec 11 (Box 27, Folder 505)
      - "Exhibition works of E. S. Paxson," carbon typescript, annotated, with index cards recording sales of Paxson art (Box 27, Folder 506)
      - List of paintings and their prices. Holograph (Box 27, Folder 507)
  - PEASE, LUTE
    - Artwork
      - "$16,000 to the Man." Watercolor and pencil, 21.3 x 35.5 cm., [1898] (Box 28, Folder 508)
      - "'All the gold that's left in this yere crick wouldn't fill the hole that's achin' my back tooth.'" Pencil drawing, 31.4 x 21.6 cm., n.d. (Box 28, Folder 509)
        Note at bottom: "From sketch of Ferguson, Last Chance Creek, July, 1899"
      - "And Sharkey Also Ran." Pen-and-ink drawing, 50.1 x 34.3 cm. (Box 28, Folder 510)
      - "'The Blue Bull Knew his Rights' (Preliminary, much reduced scale for illustration for 'Long Trail to Last Chance.' The picture will be authentic view on White Pass. The empties right.)" Pen-and-ink, wash and gouache, 35.5 x 21.9 cm. (Box 28, Folder 511)
      - "'Clean-up from some fat claim up Klondike', said Joaquin Miller. 'About 16,000 in each of those pokes.'" Pen-and-ink and charcoal, 21.6 x 35.6 cm. (Box 28, Folder 512)
        "For 'Long Trail to Last Chance.' This rough is from pen & ink sketch I made in Dawson June 5th '98"
      - "Coleman." Pen-and-ink drawing, 29.2 x 21.5 cm., 1898 (Box 28, Folder 513)
        Signed "Lute Pease Skagway '98"
      - ["Congress" holding wire cutter looking at Uncle Sam bent over under a snarl of train tracks and train on his back.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 56.2 x 44.4 cm. (Box 28, Folder 514)
      - "Curly Cox at White Horse - from life sketch." Pen-and-ink drawing, 35.9 x 21.7 cm., 1898 May (Box 28, Folder 515)
        At top: "He shot my dog for cub-b of the Yellow Braid." Pilot Cox with his blonde curls and his stout ash oar." Pencil sketch of same man on verso
      - "Doc." Pen-and-ink drawing, 31.2 x 22.9 cm. (Box 28, Folder 516)
      - "Drive On!" Pen-and-ink drawing, 56.2 x 38.1 cm. (Box 28, Folder 517)
      - "Dusted Off!" Pen-and-ink, charcoal and gouache, 35.5 x 42.5 cm. (Box 28, Folder 518)
        Signed. Stamp of Newark Evening News Ed. Dept. filled in on verso
      - "'Egochuk' 'Rough' for 'Weird Winter on Kotzebue.'" Charcoal and gouache drawing, 21.5 x 35.7 cm. (irreg.) (Box 28, Folder 519)
      - [Gold miner holding mining pan.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 32.9 x 21.4 cm. (Box 28, Folder 520)
      - "How About Cutting Costs?" Pen-and-ink, charcoal and gouache, 38.9 x 45.1 cm. (Box 28, Folder 521)
      - "I Just Couldn't get it to grow right." Pen-and-ink drawing, 28 x 18.2 cm. (Box 28, Folder 522)
        "Me - getting ready for Klondike, Fall of 97" written at bottom
      - "'I'll tell 'em what I've suffered and if they don't cry I'll lick 'em till they do!' Chap IV." Pen-and-ink drawing, 21.9 x 35.8 cm. (Box 28, Folder 523)
      - "Judgment of Solomon Wilson." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 60.8 x 45.5 cm.
        Signed. Rough pencil sketch of same scene on verso
        Stored in: Oversize box 58, folder 1127
      - [The Kaiser holding a "Note from U.S." while Uncle Sam leans against fence whittling a piece of wood.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 52.7 x 44.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 524)
      - "'Know This Feller?' Demanded the Tall One." Pastel drawing, 21.1 x 35.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 525)
        Signed. "Trial sketch (reduced scale) for 'A Night on Seventy Mile' Oil or charcoal"
      - [Man in rowboat laden with boxes and snowshoes rowing towards mountains.] Charcoal, pen-and-ink and gouache, 44 x 52.6 cm. (Box 29, Folder 526)
        Signed. "Jan 4 News" on verso
      - [Man sitting in chair next to window.] Pen-and-ink and wash, 42 x 41.9 cm., 1949 (Box 29, Folder 527)
        Signed. Stamp of Newark Sunday News on verso with Dec. 25 1949 stamped in it
      - "Miles Canyon 'jus' roared on'! Pilots Skagit Charles and Tom Bond saved their one customer. He had 'caught a crab.'" Gouache, 35.8 x 21.8 cm. (Box 29, Folder 528)
      - "Montana: 'When ye start a thing, me bye, ye'd better finish wid it.'" Pen-and-ink drawing, 32.8 x 21.4 cm. (Box 29, Folder 529)
        Signed "Lute Pease from sketch White Pass Trail '98"
      - "Must face it." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 35.2 x 28.6 cm. (Box 29, Folder 530)
      - "Necessity and the Man." Pen-and-ink, charcoal, and colored pencil drawing, 36.1 x 45 cm. (Box 29, Folder 531)
      - "Neptune to Frightfulness." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 61 x 48.5 cm.
      - "'Nigger Jim' Doughterty, famous stampeder. A powerful, tireless trail man, he was foremost in many of the wild races for supposed new discoveries." Charcoal drawing, 36.2 x 20.5 cm., n.d. (Box 29, Folder 532)
      - "Old Dave 'Doc Porter.'" Pen-and-ink drawing, 31.9 x 19.2 cm. (Box 29, Folder 533)
        "Chapter VIII. Roughs to Illustrate Sourdough Bread 'Quest of Jack McQuesten's 'Telluride Gold.''"
      - "'Old Uncle Sam' Patch and his Place. 15.7 cm. (irreg.), 1898 (Box 29, Folder 534)
        Signed "Pease Forty Mile '98"
      - "One glance at my contraption provoked his chuckle. ("Rough" for illustration. "A Thousand Cords of Wood.")" Pen-and-ink, charcoal and gouache, 35.7 x 21.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 535)
        At top "(Martin Deadfall)" At bottom: "Thorson wore caribous skin - Groundhog case at my martin trap. 'Big 'nough for a wolverine!'"
      - "Over the Top for Italia Irredenta." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 53.6 x 43.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 536)
        Signed. Pencil drawing on verso of a soldier "New Jersey's Quota" going over the top, labeled "Indifference"
      - [Prospector with mule loaded down with bags "Democratic Congress," "Domestic Plans," "Bi-partisan Foreign Policy" looking in direction pointed by sign "Next 4 Years."] Pen-and-ink, charcoal and gouache, 36.7 x 44.8 cm. (Box 29, Folder 537)
      - "Room For More, B'Gosh!" Pen-and-ink drawing, 51 x 41.8 cm. (Box 29, Folder 538)
      - "A Salesman Calls." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 36.4 x 28.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 539)
      - "Seventh Annual Rose Festival. Portland Oregon June 9 to 14 1913." Color print poster, 53.2 x 39.7 cm. (Box 29, Folder 540)
      - "Seventh Annual Rose Festival. Portland Oregon June 9 to 14 1913. Low Rates On All Lines." Color print poster, 69 x 53 cm.
        "Bushong & Co. Litho., Portland, Ore." Written at bottom: "Prize Card or Poster I did this at my lodgings in Milner Blvd. Portland Jan 1913"
      - "Shake, Rockefeller!" Pen-and-ink drawing, 28.8 x 19.1 cm. (Box 29, Folder 541)
        Signed. Pen-and-ink drawing of two men in river crossed out on verso
      - [Ship "U.S. Merchant Marine" sinking with "Former National Indifference" in sky above ship, and "Impractical Legislation" in sea below.] Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 56.1 x 46.9 cm. (Box 29, Folder 542)
      - "Storm Warning." Charcoal and gouache drawing, 38.4 x 46.7 cm., [1944] (Box 29, Folder 543)
        Signed cartoon. "In the Shadow of Coming Events" title crossed out below
        Stamp of Newark Evening News Ed. Dept. filled in on verso
      - "The 'Sweeper' and the meat. ('A Night on Seventymile')" Pen-and-ink, charcoal and gouache drawing, 21.3 x 35.6 cm. (Box 29, Folder 544)
      - "The Terrible Roundup." Pen-and-ink, charcoal and gouache drawing, 30.1 x 37.4 cm. (Box 29, Folder 545)
        "To Albert F. Reid with regards of Lute Pease"
      - "Time to Operate." Pen-and-ink, charcoal, and gouache drawing, 37.2 x 48.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 546)
        Signed. Stamp of Newark Evening News Ed. Dept. on verso
      - "To build a raft - 'I was tickled to show off to Ol' Doc.'" Pen-and-ink, gouache, and charcoal drawing, 21.5 x 33.3 cm. (Box 29, Folder 547)
        At top: "'Rough' to illustrate 'In [text chopped off] of Jack McQuesten's 'Telluride Gold.''"
      - "Victory's 'in the bag,' already." Pen-and-ink and charcoal drawing, 35.7 x 29 cm., [1932] (Box 29, Folder 548)
      - "We braced the tent with driftwood as the blizzard steadily buried us deeper ("Kee-nuk-shok-a-tok-tuk")" Pen-and-ink and watercolor drawing, 21.5 x 28.8 cm. (Box 29, Folder 549)
        At bottom: "'Just another Injun Story' Kobuk Juna and I fought off the snow." Accompanied by slightly different drawing clipped from a newspaper
      - [White House with sign on tower built on top: "White House. A Few Vacancies Reserved for Deserving Party Workers.] Pen-and-ink and crayon drawing, 36.3 x 48.5 cm. (Box 29, Folder 550)
      - "Who, Me?" Lithograph, 23.3 x 26.8 cm., n.d. (Box 29, Folder 551)
        "Lute Pease's Pulitzer Prize Cartoon Published in The News, Under the Caption "Who, Me?" April 6, 1948"
      - "You can get anything from 'yes' and no x 35.6 cm. (Box 29, Folder 552)
        Signed. At top: "'Rough' for illustration 'The Pikes & the Candlebox' ('Weird Winter on Kotzebue')"
    - Printed Material
      - Campaign card "Lute Pease, Progressive Nominee for County Commissioner", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 553)
      - Pacific Monthly covers by Pease, 1906-09 (Box 30, Folder 554)
      - Other Pacific Monthly covers, 1911 (Box 30, Folder 555)
      - Clippings of Pease's artwork, 1900-58 (Box 30, Folder 556)
      - Clippings of articles by Pease, 1948-58 (Box 30, Folder 557)
      - Clippings about Pease, 1896-1958 (Box 30, Folder 558)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1926-35, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 559)
    - Photographs
      - Lute Pease, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 560)
      - Lute Pease and Mark Twain, 1895 (Box 30, Folder 561)
      - Lute Pease and others (Box 30, Folder 562)
      - Office and staff of the Pacific Monthly, 18.5 x 24.2 cm. on mount 27.2 x 34.6 cm. (Box 30, Folder 563)
        Stored also in: Oversize box 57, folder 1114
      - Miners and homesteaders in Alaska (Box 30, Folder 564)
      - Native Alaskans, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 565)
      - Dawson City, 1899 (Box 30, Folder 566)
        Photograph by Asahel Curtis
      - Pease Valley, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 567)
      - Photoreproduction of drawing of men in snow, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 568)
    - Correspondence
      - Stevens, Horace to Lute Pease, 1919 Sep 9 (Box 30, Folder 569)
  - WEBBER, JOHN
    - "Inhabitants of Norton Sound, and their Habitations." Engraving, plate mark 25.4 x 40.1 cm. on sheet 38.9 x 52.3 cm. (Box 31, Folder 570)
      "J. Webber del. B.T. Pouncy sc."
    - "Inhabitants of Norton Sound, and their Habitations." Engraving, plate mark 25.4 x 40.1 cm. on sheet 40.4 x 55.9 cm. (Box 31, Folder 571)
      "J. Webber del. B. T. Pouncy, sc."
    - "The Inside of a House, in Oonalashka." Engraving, plate mark 25.6 x 40.4 cm. on sheet 40.5 x 55.8 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 572)
      "J. Webber del. W. Sharp sculp."
    - "The Inside of a Winter Habitation, in Kamtschatka." Engraving, plate mark 25.9 x 41.5 cm. on sheet 37.7 x 52.3 cm. (Box 31, Folder 573)
    - "A Man of Kamtschatka." Engraving, plate mark 30.4 x 23.8 cm. on sheet 52.3 x 38.2 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 574)
      "J. Webber del. W. Sharp sc."
    - "A Man of Kamtschatka, Travelling in Winter." Engraving, plate mark 25.1 x 40.6 cm. on sheet 37.5 x 52.1 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 575)
      "J. Webber del. S. Middiman, sc."
    - "A Man of Nootka Sound." Engraving, plate mark 30.3 x 23.9 cm. on sheet 55.8 x 41.1 cm. (Box 31, Folder 576)
    - "A Man of Prince William's Sound." Engraving, plate mark 31 x 24.2 cm. on sheet 55.9 x 40.2 cm. (Box 31, Folder 577)
      "J. Webber del. J. Bafire sculpt."
    - "Natives of Oonalashka, and their Habitations." Engraving, plate mark 25.6 x 41.4 cm. on sheet 38.6 x 52.2 cm. (Box 31, Folder 578)
      "J. Webber del. J. Hall & S. Middiman sc."
    - "Sea Horses." Engraving, 27.1 x 41 cm. on sheet 43.5 x 59.5 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 579)
      "Drawn by J. Webber. The Figures by J. Heath."
    - "A Sea Otter." Etching, plate mark 19.9 x 26.7 cm. on sheet 38.3 x 52.1 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 580)
      "J. Webber del. Mazell sculp."
    - "Summer and Winter Habitations, in Kamtschatka." Engraving, plate mark 24.5 x 40.4 cm. on sheet 38 x 52.3 cm. (Box 31, Folder 581)
      "J. Webber del. S. Smith, sc."
    - "Various Articles, at Nootka Sound." Engraving, plate mark 20.4 x 27.5 cm. on sheet 41.8 x 55.8 cm. (Box 31, Folder 582)
      "J. Webber del. J. Record sculpt."
    - "A View at Bolcheretzkoi in Kamtschatka." Engraving, plate mark 24.1 x 34.5 cm. on sheet 37.8 x 52.3 cm. (Box 31, Folder 583)
      "J. Webber del. P. Benezech sc."
    - "A View of the Habitations in Nootka Sound." Two engravings, plate mark 25.7 x 40.1 cm. on sheet 40.9 x 59.1 cm. and smaller (Box 31, Folder 584)
      "J. Webber del. S. Smith sculp."
    - "A View of the Snug Corner Cove, in Prince William's Sound." Engraving, plate mark 25.4 x 40.3 cm. on sheet 40.6 x 56 cm. (Box 31, Folder 585)
      "J. Webber del. W. Ellis sculpt."
    - "A View of the Town and Harbour of St. Peter and St. Paul, in Kamtschatka." Engraving, plate mark 25.2 x 53 cm. on sheet 39.9 x 59.9 cm. (Box 31, Folder 586)
    - "A White Bear." Etching, plate mark 21.6 x 26.9 cm. on sheet 37.9 x 52.3 cm. (Box 31, Folder 587)
    - "A Woman of Kamtschatka." Engraving, plate mark 30.1 x 24.2 cm. on sheet 52.2 x 37.6 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 588)
    - "A Woman of Prince William's Sound." Engraving, plate mark 30.4 x 24.5 cm. on sheet 55.9 x 40.9 cm. (Box 31, Folder 589)
  - WINTER, DANIEL
    - "77 Jackson St. S.F. Cal." Watercolor over pencil, 18.6 x 21.8 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 590)
      Depicts house and sign painting shop belonging to Winter
    - [The Arrival of the United States War Steamer Conveying the Japanese Embassy, at Honolulu, Sandwich Islands.] Pencil with watercolor, 16.4 x 25.8 cm., [1860] (Box 31, Folder 591)
    - "The Arrival of the United States War Steamer Conveying the Japanese Embassy, at Honolulu, Sandwich Islands. From a sketch by Daniel Winter." Wood engraving, 23.4 x 27.9 cm., 1860 May 19 (Box 31, Folder 592)
      Published in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Weekly
    - "Bunyarrambite Waterfall near Melbourne." Pencil drawing with gouache, 19.8 x 17 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 593)
    - "Honolulu, Oahu, S.I." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 16.5 x 22.9 cm. (Box 31, Folder 594)
    - "Kalo Patch. T. R." Pencil drawing, 17.2 x 23.3 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 595)
    - "Kohala Loa." Pencil drawing with wash, 17.6 x 25.5 cm., n.d. (Box 31, Folder 596)
      "Copy sent to Sister Elizabeth" at bottom of mat. Signed. Title from mat
    - "Lai Kui Rai Tui Society Is." Pencil drawing with gouache, 17.2 x 25.7 cm., n.d. (Box 32, Folder 597)
    - "Lava Hills S.I." Pencil drawing with gouache, 16.3 x 26.5 cm., n.d. (Box 32, Folder 598)
    - "The Lily." Pencil drawing, 19.2 x 14.9 cm. (Box 32, Folder 599)
    - [Natives eating in front of hut on a tropical island.] Pencil and watercolor, 17.5 x 26.4 cm. (Box 32, Folder 600)
      Decorations in upper corners of drawing in watercolor depicting small "Holy Bibles"
    - [Oxford?] Pencil drawing, 16.7 x 22.1 cm. (Box 32, Folder 601)
    - "Pali South Islands." Pencil drawing, 16.6 x 24.7 cm. (Box 32, Folder 602)
    - "Parpeta, Society Is." Pencil and watercolor, 24.6 x 30.2 cm. (Box 32, Folder 603)
    - "Pearl Harbour & Valley." Pencil drawing with gouache, 17 x 27.3 cm., n.d. (Box 32, Folder 604)
    - [Self-portrait.] Pencil drawing, 21 x 17.5 cm., n.d. (Box 32, Folder 605)
      Title from Stenzel's notes
    - "Raivavai Island. 23' South. 148° West Longitude. Lying W.N.W." Pencil drawing, 23.5 x 30.2 cm. (Box 32, Folder 606)
    - [Spanish woman.] Watercolor, oval image 24.2 x 30.1 cm., n.d. (Box 32, Folder 607)
    - "Wahina." Pencil and watercolor, 14.9 x 20.2 cm. (Box 32, Folder 608)
    - "Wahinis." Pencil and watercolor, 16.7 x 25.6 cm. (Box 32, Folder 609)
    - "Waikiki Diamond Head Sandwich Islands." Pencil drawing, 16.1 x 23.1 cm. (Box 32, Folder 610)
    - Miscellaneous pencil sketches of signs, including one in color pencil for "Danl. Winter, Sign & Ornamental Painter", sketches of a child and a carriage, 20.5 x 28 cm. and smaller (Box 32, Folder 611)
- Other Artwork, 1790-1966; Series IV; 24.06; (15 boxes)
  Series IV, Other Artwork is organized by artist, with unidentified works listed at the end of the series. Within each subseries, the material is organized by title.
  - ABRAMS, KATHERINE DELANEY
    - [Totem poles.] Watercolor, 12.5 x 20.1 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 612)
  - AGATE, ALFRED T.
    - "Astoria." Steel engraving, 10 x 16 cm., n.d.
      Stored in: Oversize box 56, folder 1101
    - "Fording at Yamhill River Oregon." Watercolor, 21.7 x 28.6 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 613)
      Signed with initials device. "Party crossing the Ford on the way from Fort Vancouver to California" written on verso
  - ALEXANDER, W.
    - "Four remarkable, supported Poles, in Port Townshend, Gulph of Georgia." Engraving, 20.8 x 26.7 cm., 1798 (Box 33, Folder 614)
      "W. Alexander del. from a Sketch taken on the Spot by J. Sykes. J. Heath Sculp."
    - "Mount Rainier, from the South part of Admiralty Inlet." Engraving, 21.1 x 27.5 cm., 1798 (Box 33, Folder 615)
      "W. Alexander del. from a Sketch taken on the Spot by J. Sykes. J. Landseer Sculp."
  - AMANN, CHARLES R.
    - [Harbor view with sailing ships.] Oil painting, 36.4 x 48.6 cm. in frame 52.7 x 64.9 cm., n.d.
  - AUGIER, S.
    - "Across the Continent. Westward the Course of Empire Takes its Way." Colored etching, 34 x 43.9 cm., n.d.
    - "The Rocky Mountains." Colored etching, plate mark 33.6 x 43.9 cm. on sheet 52 x 65.2 cm., n.d.
  - BACHELDER, JOHN BADGER
    - "Gettysburg Battlefield." Colored lithograph, 71 x 101 cm., n.d.
      "Endicott & Co. Lith."
  - BAILLIE, JAMES
    - "The Great Fight, between Tom Hyer & Yankee Sullivan, for $10,000." Chromolithograph, 34.7 x 49.8 cm., n.d.
      "Presented by the New York Illustrated Times the leading and best Sporting Journal in America"
  - BAKER, P. KINCHELOE
    - "Blue Wing." Etching, plate mark 19.9 x 12.9 cm. on sheet 31.9 x 24.5 cm., 1887 (Box 33, Folder 616)
  - BAMFORD, THOMAS
    - [Shoreline with boats on shore and five figures.] Oil painting, 22.7 x 29.1 cm. (Box 33, Folder 617)
    - [Victoria West.] Watercolor, 23.5 x 17 cm. (Box 33, Folder 618)
  - BARNES, C. M.
    - "At the lake July 4th Friends. tried & true." Watercolor, 22 x 31.4 cm. (Box 33, Folder 619)
  - BARTLETT, W. H.
    - "The Ferry at Brooklyn, New York." Steel engraving, colored, 19.8 x 26.6 cm. (Box 33, Folder 620)
      "London, Published for the Proprietors, by Geo. Virtue... G.K. Richardson, engraver"
    - "The Palisades - Hudson River." Steel engraving, colored, 20.8 x 26.8 cm., 1837 (Box 33, Folder 621)
      "London, Published for the Proprietors, by Geo. Virtue. C. Cousen, engraver"
  - BEARD, JAMES CARTER
    - [Elk grazing.] Etching, 21.6 x 31.4 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 622)
  - BEARD, W. H. (WILLIAM HOLBROOK)
    - "Great Suspension Bridge at Lewiston and Queenston. Over the Niagara River six Miles below Niagara Falls. The Largest in the World, Built in 1850." Tinted lithograph, 38 x 53.2 cm. (Box 33, Folder 623)
      "Lith. of Endicott & Co. N.Y. Painted by Wm. H. Beard"
  - BEECHER, HARRIET FOSTER
    - "Duwamish Indian Camp." Watercolor, visible image 12.3 x 33.7 cm., 1896 (Box 33, Folder 624)
    - [Native American fishing boats.] Watercolor, 21.1 x 43.2 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 625)
      Possibly by Beecher
    - "Point Hudson." Watercolor, 17.1 x 35.5 cm. (Box 33, Folder 626)
    - "Port Madison looking out of harbor." Pencil drawing with gouache, 24.8 x 32.3 cm., 1882 Mar 23 (Box 33, Folder 627)
      Signed "H.F.B."